<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1" standalone="yes"?>

<helpfile>
 <entry>
  <key>groupperm</key>
  <title>Group Permissions</title>
  <text>
 Select the permissions that you want to grant to the group. If you are modifying
 a group, the checked permissions will be added, but unchecked ones will not be
 deleted unless you also check the box labeled Remove Existing Permissions.
  </text>
 </entry>

 <entry>
  <key>groupentry</key>
  <title>Group Name and Description</title>
  <text>
   Enter the name and description of the group. The name should be short and one
   word. The description can be longer and multiple words. 
  </text>
 </entry>

 <entry>
  <key>grouptutorial</key>
  <title>Short tutorial on groups</title>
  <text>
Access to documents within the DocDB is controlled in several ways. A document
may be tagged as accessible to a subset of groups. Additionally, each group may
have a list of subordinate groups. Anything marked viewable by a subordinate
is also viewable by its superior group. (This relationship does not extend to
more than one generation, though.)<p/> Each group also has a flag determining
whether that group is allowed to create new  or modify existing documents. If a
group is allowed to view a document, it can change that document (assuming they
also have the create/modify flag set). These group names must match those in
the <b>.htpasswd</b> file although the comparison is not case sensitive.
  </text>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <key>child</key>
  <title>Subordinate groups</title>
  <text>
Select the groups you want to be subordinates of this group. This means that the
dominant group will be able to see and change all documents that these groups
can.
  </text>
 </entry>

 <entry>
  <key>parent</key>
  <title>Group</title>
  <text>
Select the group you want to delete or modify. If you want to modify, fill out
the names and permissions that you want to change.
  </text>
 </entry>

 <entry>
  <key>admaction</key>
  <title>Administrative actions</title>
  <text>
Select the action you want to perform on the list. You can either modify an
existing entry, create a new entry, or delete an entry. Then fill out the rest
of form.
  </text>
 </entry>

 <entry>
  <key>instentry</key>
  <title>Institution entry</title>
  <text>
Fill out both the short name, (i.e. Illinois) and the long name (i.e. University
of Illinois) for the institution.
  </text>
 </entry>

 <entry>
<key>notifyauthor</key>
<title>E-mail notification authors</title>
  <text>
Select which people you want to be notified about when they are listed as
authors on documents.  Immediate notification will send you e-mail on each
document as it is entered. Daily and weekly notifications send out lists of
documents you are interested in every night or week.<p/>

You can select any combination of authors for each of the three
periods.
  </text>
 </entry>

 <entry>
<key>notifykeyword</key>
<title>E-mail notification keywords</title>
  <text>
Select the keywords that you want to be notified when they are entered on
documents. The keywords are case insensitive, but otherwise must match
<b>exactly</b>. Immediate notification will send you e-mail on each
document as it is entered. Daily and weekly notifications send out lists of
documents you are interested in every night or week.<p/>

You can select any combination of keywords for each of the three
periods.
  </text>
 </entry>

 <entry>
<key>notifytopic</key>
<title>E-mail notification topics</title>
  <text>
Select the topics or subtopics that you want to be notified about for the
selected time period. Immediate notification will send you e-mail on each
document as it is entered. Daily and weekly notifications send out lists of
documents you are interested in every night or week.<p/>

You can select any combination of topics and subtopics for each of the three
periods.
  </text>
 </entry>

 <entry>
<key>overdatepref</key>
<title>Override submit date</title>
  <text>
Use this option if you want to (by default) be able to set the date and time
for documents written in the past. This is useful mainly for those entering
lots of old documents.
  </text>
 </entry>

 <entry>
<key>namepref</key>
<title>Name</title>
  <text>
Select your name from the list. When you create a new document, you will be
automatically selected as the requester and author.
  </text>
 </entry>

 <entry>
<key>displaymode</key>
<title>Sort by</title>
  <text>
This controls how the list of documents is sorted and what is shown on the
one-line summary of the document. "By Date" is usually used for generic
documents and "By Author" is useful for meetings.
  </text>
 </entry>

 <entry>
<key>filename</key>
<title>File Name</title>
  <text>
When updating the database information on a document, you can't rename the
files, but you can redescribe them. These are the names of the files in your
document.
  </text>
 </entry>

 <entry>
<key>dynamictopic</key>
<title>Topics</title>
  <text>
Using this control you can select either topics or sub-topics for the
document(s) you are searching for. You can select topics on the left and
sub-topics on the right. Selecting a topic on the left will limit your choices
on the right (assuming you have Javascript turned on). 
<p/>
Selecting any sub-topic on the right ignore its parent topic on the left. 
This means that if you have <i>Meetings</i> and
<i>Detectors</i>
selected on the left and <i>Detectors:Straws</i> selected on the right, your
search will be performed on <i>Detectors:Straws</i> and <i>Meetings</i>. But,
even if you have "OR" selected for "Within Fields," you won't get documents for
detectors other than straws.  
  </text>
 </entry>

 <entry>
<key>beforeafterdate</key>
<title>Last Modified Between</title>
  <text>
Use these two menus to select a date range for the document(s) you are looking
for. You can leave either the start or end completely blank for an open ended
search. <p/>
You can also leave months and/or days blank on one or both menus to perform
searches between the beginning and end of years and months (whichever is
appropriate). Unpredictable
results may occur if, for instance, you leave the month blank but select a day
of the month.
  </text>
 </entry>

 <entry>
<key>doctypemulti</key>
<title>Document Type</title>
  <text>
Select the types of documents you are looking for. Note that regardless of the
setting of <b>Within Fields</b> this search will be performed with a logical
OR.
  </text>
 </entry>

 <entry>
<key>requestersearch</key>
<title>Requester</title>
  <text>
Select the people who might have initially requested or requested a modification
to the document you are looking for. Note that regardless of the setting of
<b>Within Fields</b> this search will be performed with a logical OR.
  </text>
 </entry>

 <entry>
<key>wordsearch</key>
<title>Text Searches</title>
  <text>
These fields allow you to search on the various text items in the database.
The following modes are used to search for information:
<ul>
 <li><b>Any words as sub-string: </b>The information you enter is broken into
 words (delimited by spaces) and the field you are searching in is required to
 match one or more of these words as a substring (<i>lock</i> will match
 <i>lock</i> and <i>block</i>).</li>
 <li><b>All words as sub-string: </b>The information you enter is broken into
 words (delimited by spaces) and the field you are searching in is required to
 match all of these words as substrings (in any order).</li> 
</ul> 
  </text>
 </entry>

 <entry>
<key>logictype</key>
<title>Between Fields vs. Within Fields</title>
  <text>
Two types of logic can be used to refine your search. <p/>

The setting for <b>Between Fields</b> lets you select AND or OR between
elements on the form. For instance, if you select and Author and a Topic, you
can either find documents by that author AND on that topic or by that author OR
on that topic. AND is the default.<p/>

The setting for <b>Within Fields</b> determines what happens when, for instance,
you select two authors. You can either require that both authors are present on
the paper (AND) or either author is present (OR). OR is the
default. Note that this setting
doesn't apply to text searches (since they use their own syntax). Also, for
Requester and Document Type, multiple settings on the document are not
possible, so these searches are <b>always</b> done with an OR. 
  </text>
 </entry>

 <entry>
<key>keywords</key>
<title>Keywords</title>
  <text>
   Keywords are used to further classify documents below the sub-topic level.
   Keywords should be seperated by spaces. Compound words should use a dash or
   under-score to connect words. 
  </text>
 </entry>

 <entry>
<key>replacefiles</key>
<title>Replace Duplicate Files</title>
  <text>
If you select this option, any files you add which duplicate file names of
existing files will completely replace the old files (no backup will be kept). Yuu
should <b>not</b> be using this option avoid creating a new version of a
document, even if only minor changes have been made. This option is, instead,
intended for making minor fixes to presentation formats and the like. 
Disk space is cheap, mistakes are not.
<p/>
Please use this option responsibly. 
  </text>
 </entry>

 <entry>
<key>authormanual</key>
<title>Authors</title>
  <text>
Type the names of the authors here. Put each author on a new line. Use full last
names and first names or initials. Each author entered will checked against the
database and a <b>unique</b> match must be found for <b>all</b> authors before the document
will be added. Requiring a unique match means that for people who share a last
name, the first name must be fully specified. Entered middle initials are
ignored.
<p/>
If you would prefer to select the author names from a list, select "Selectable
List" as the author selection mode from the advanced form on the document DB
home page.
  </text>
 </entry>

 <entry>
<key>startdate</key>
<title>Start Date</title>
  <text>
Select the date of the start of the conference.
  </text>
 </entry>

 <entry>
<key>enddate</key>
<title>End Date</title>
  <text>
Select the date of the end of the conference.
  </text>
 </entry>

 <entry>
<key>location</key>
<title>Location</title>
  <text>
Type in the location of the conference. City, state (if in the USA), and
country.
  </text>
 </entry>

 <entry>
<key>confurl</key>
<title>URL</title>
  <text>
Type in the URL for the conference's homepage. Please include the http:// or
https:// at the beginning.
  </text>
 </entry>

 <entry>
<key>docnumber</key>
<title>Document Number</title>
  <text>
This is the number (six digits or less) of the document you want to act on. If
you can supply a version number, that is always in a seperate field, don't type
it here.
  </text>
 </entry>

 <entry>
<key>description</key>
<title>Description</title>
  <text>
This is a short description of each file. This description will appear in the
hyperlink in the document summary. For instance, you might describe a .ppt file
as "PowerPoint of the conference talk" and a .ps file as "The proceedings for
the conference." The description is optional, but recommended.
  </text>
 </entry>

 <entry>
<key>localfile</key>
<title>File</title>
  <text>
This is a file on your local computer. You can type in a full file name or press
browse to go find the file.
  </text>
 </entry>

 <entry>
<key>remoteurl</key>
<title>URL</title>
  <text>
In this box, enter a URL available on the web. The file will be fetched from
this URL and stored on the server. The URL must be a full URL, with http:// at
the beginning and a file name at the end (cannot end in "/"). The https and ftp
protocols may also work.
<p/>
If the URL is protected, enter the username and password used to access the
URL. The username and password are not saved.
  </text>
 </entry>

 <entry>
  <key>modifytypes</key>
  <title>Modification Actions</title>
  <text>
There are five ways to modify a document:
<ol>
<li>Reserve a document #: Select this option if you want a number for a document
you are going to write, but don't have a draft of the document.</li>
<li>New document: You have a new document ready to be put into the database that
has not been entered before.</li>
<li>Update document: You have a new version of a document already in the
database. You will also be able to change any of the information in the database
about the document. You must supply a document number to modify.</li>
<li>Update database information: The document hasn't changed, but the
information about it has. For example, it's now published so you want to add that
information. You must supply a document number to modify.</li>
<li>Add/Replace files: You forgot a file that belongs with the document or
something minor has changed in one of the files. To add or replace files, use
the customize box at the bottom of the page.<p/>Replacing files should be done
with caution since no backup is kept. Please do not use this capability to
avoid creating a new version of a document when that is more appropriate. Disk
space is cheap, mistakes are not.</li>
</ol>
Select the type of modification appropriate to your situation
  </text>
 </entry>

 <entry>
  <key>uploadmethod</key>
  <title>Upload Methods</title>
  <text>
You can upload documents by two different methods. 
<ol>
<li>You can upload files from
your local computer </li>
<li>You can upload files by supplying a URL. In this case, the database
system downloads the document from the location you specify. </li>
</ol>
In both cases the document is ultimately stored on the document database webserver.
  </text>
 </entry>

 <entry>
  <key>uploadtype</key>
  <title>Upload Types</title>
  <text>
You can upload three different types of documents. 
<ol>
<li>You can upload a single file. This is the default. </li>
<li>You can upload a document consisting of multiple files, such as PowerPoint
and PDF by selecting "Multiple" and filling in the "# of files" option with the
number of files you want to upload. </li>
<li>You can upload an archive file containing all the files in your document.
However, only one of those files will be directly accessible. For example, use
this option to upload a group of linked web pages. You can upload files in
.tar, .tar.gz, .tgz, or .zip format.</li>
</ol>
  </text>
 </entry>

 <entry>
  <key>topicoption</key>
  <title>Topic Selection</title>
  <text>
You can either select the subtopic(s) for your document from one long list or
from a number of shorter lists split up by topic. 
  </text>
 </entry>

 <entry>
  <key>authoroption</key>
  <title>Author Selection</title>
  <text>
There are two methods of entering the authors for a document. The first is
selecting the authors from a list of all possible authors. The second is to type
into a form the names of the authors. <i>However</i> for your document to be
accepted, every author that you entered must successfully match with an author
in the database. The second method has not been implemented.
  </text>
 </entry>

 <entry>
  <key>dateoverride</key>
  <title>Overriding the submission date</title>
  <text>
Use this option to set the date and time for a document written in the past.
Unless you are submitting a document from the old database or one written a long
time ago, you should probably not check this. By default, new documents are
entered with the current date and time.
  </text>
 </entry>

 <entry>
  <key>main</key>
  <title>Main Files</title>
  <text>
Files that the database knows about are classified as "Main" or "Other." Main
files are typically the ones you want people to look at. As an example, the
top file of several linked HTML files is a "Main File," the others are "Other
Files."
  </text>
 </entry>

 <entry>
  <key>overdate</key>
  <title>Date and Time</title>
  <text>
Use these menus to set the date and time for a document written in the past.
Unless you are submitting a document from the old database or one written a long
time ago, you should not check "Override date" and you will not have to use this
control. For your convenience, the date has been set to approximately the
current time.
  </text>
 </entry>

 <entry>
  <key>title</key>
  <title>Title</title>
  <text>
This is the initial title of of your document. This option must be supplied for
when placing a document into the database and when reserving a document number.
  </text>
 </entry>

 <entry>
  <key>requester</key>
  <title>Requester</title>
  <text>
This is the name of the person who is requesting the document number or placing
the document in the database. In other words, this is you. This option must be 
supplied when reserving a document number, placing a document into the database,
or updating a document.
  </text>
 </entry>

 <entry>
  <key>pubinfo</key>
  <title>Publication Information</title>
  <text>
In this field, include any additional publication information that can't be
placed in the boxes above. Valid URLs entered here will be linked for the user. This field is optional.
<p/>
If your document is in a journal or preprint archive that you feel should be
added to the list in the DocDB, please contact an administrator.
  </text>
 </entry>

 <entry>
  <key>reference</key>
  <title>References</title>
  <text>
In this space, add any references to journals or archives for your
document. If the journal or archive does not exist and you feel should be
added to the list in the DocDB, please contact an administrator.
<p/>
If you already have more than one reference for your document, add the first one
now. When the document is entered, select Update DB Info and add the other ones.
Each time you "Update DB Info" you are given the chance to add one additional
reference.
  </text>
 </entry>

 <entry>
  <key>abstract</key>
  <title>Abstract</title>
  <text>
Include here an abstract of your document. A short description of the topic(s)
discussed. This is optional during the reservation stage, but required when
adding or updating a document.
  </text>
 </entry>

 <entry>
  <key>fileupload</key>
  <title>File upload</title>
  <text>
This field will upload a file from your local computer to the database server.
Usually you will press the "Browse" button to select, from your local file
system, the file to be uploaded. The base file name cannot contain a back slash
"\" or a forward slash "/" to preserve compatibility with both Windows and
Unix. 
<p/>
You can also enter a short description of each file, which will appear in the
summary of the document. The description is optional.
<p/>
If there are more upload boxes than you need, just leave the last ones blank.
<p/>
If you want to submit a URL rather than a local file, use the Customize
Insert/Modify functions to select your type of upload.
  </text>
 </entry>

 <entry>
  <key>authors</key>
  <title>Authors</title>
  <text>
If entering a new document, select all the authors of the document. 
If you would prefer to type in the author names individually, select "Text
Field" as the author selection mode from the advanced form on the document DB
home page.<p/>
If searching for a document, select the authors appropriately for your setting
of <b>Within Fields</b>.<p/>
To select multiple authors either click
(Netscape 4.x) or CTRL-click (Netscape 6.x, Internet Explorer) on the author
names.
  </text>
 </entry>

 <entry>
  <key>topics</key>
  <title>Topics</title>
  <text>
Select all the topics and subtopics for the document. To select multiple topics
either click (Netscape 4.x) or CTRL-click (Netscape 6.x, Internet Explorer) on
the topic names. Note that there are two ways to enter topics, either from one
big long list or from several shorter lists. You can select the other mode from
the customize form on the main page.
  </text>
 </entry>

 <entry>
  <key>security</key>
  <title>Security</title>
  <text>
Select which username/password pairs you want to allow access to your document.
To select more than one pair, either click (Netscape 4.x) or CTRL-click
(Netscape 6.x, Internet Explorer) on them. You can make a document public by
leaving all selections blank. Selecting "Public" doesn't actually do anything
except generate a warning if you combine "Public" with another name.
  </text>
 </entry>

 <entry>
  <key>doctype</key>
  <title>Document Type</title>
  <text>
Select which kind of document this is. This has nothing to do with the format of
the document. I.e. a PowerPoint file isn't <i>necessarily</i> a "Talk."
  </text>
 </entry>

 <entry>
  <key>majortopics</key>
  <title>Major Topics</title>
  <text>
Select the Major topic which is the parent of the minor, or subtopic you are
entering. New major topics can currently only be entered into the database
directly (there is no web form).
  </text>
 </entry>

 <entry>
  <key>shortdescription</key>
  <title>Short Description of Subtopic or Conference</title>
  <text>
This is the text that appears in the selectable boxes and in the ShowDocument
script.
<p/>
For conferences, this should be the short name of the conference, like "High
Energy 6."
  </text>
 </entry>

 <entry>
  <key>longdescription</key>
  <title>Long Description of Subtopic or Conference</title>
  <text>
This is a longer description of the topic, if needed. If not, it should be the
same as the short description. While this isn't used now, it might be in the
future.
<p/>
For conferences, this should be the full name of the conference, like "The Sixth
International Conference of Interactions at High Energy."
  </text>
 </entry>

 <entry>
  <key>institution</key>
  <title>Institution</title>
  <text>
The institution the author you are entering is associated with.
  </text>
 </entry>

 <entry>
  <key>authorentry</key>
  <title>Entering the Author's Name</title>
  <text>
Fill in the fields for first and last name as well as the middle initials, if
needed. 
  </text>
 </entry>

 <entry>
  <key>httpupload</key>
  <title>Upload by URL</title>
  <text>
Enter a URL for your document. The file will be fetched from this URL and
stored on the server. The URL must be a full URL, with http:// at the beginning
and a file name at the end (cannot end in "/"). The https and ftp protocols may
also work.
<p/>
If the URL is password protected, enter the username and
password for the URL here. The username and password are NOT saved.
<p/>
You can also enter a short description of each file, which will appear in the
summary of the document. The description is optional.
  </text>
 </entry>

</helpfile>
